<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HoffsMH</title>
    <description>Small blog for me, the learning web developer
</description>
    <link>http://www.mhecker.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mhecker.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:10:47 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:10:47 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Robo loader</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is about a game I made with javascript canvas. In the game you play as a robot who&amp;#39;s job it is to put stuff on conveyor belts for puny humans to work on. The whole thing was an effort to understand some of the basics of design and balancing for games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common thing seen in video games is that parts of their mechanics can be seen as modular and a game in and of themselves.
A real life example of this might be that you are walking down the street while trying to go somewhere (the game as a whole), and
you have to watch your feet and avoid stepping on cracks(mini-game).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HoffsMH/robo-loader&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/robo-loader&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;So I really like World of Warcraft.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And WoW has such a mini-game.
Game balancing also really interest me too
so I tried to distill the basic mechanics of this of this mini-game into a javascript canvas game. so I could turn some knobs and see how they affect the way it plays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;The things I was interested in were:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pacing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;difficulty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;depth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game can be played &lt;a href=&quot;/robo-loader&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Please note the game might look different now than at the time of this post but the basic mechanics will still be in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Basics:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are a robot that works in a factory that has a number of horizontal Lanes( 4 in this picture). Inside of each is a &amp;quot;conveyor belt&amp;quot; with a number of cells. The cells move to the right and carry whatever is placed on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/robo-loader/basic-game.gif&quot; alt=&quot;basic game&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the left side of the screen is a &amp;quot;Loading Area&amp;quot; where we can put a certain amount of &amp;quot;material&amp;quot; down on a given Conveyor Belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/robo-loader/red-3-game.gif&quot; alt=&quot;red 3&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we just put down 3 red blobs worth of material. The numbers on the left mean that the next time we put down a red material on that lane we will only put down 2 blobs worth of red material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets look at the next game mechanic...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/robo-loader/workers-intro-game.gif&quot; alt=&quot;workers intro&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The white boxes represent the workers in this factory. The workers will move to the left while they have nothing to work on. If a single worker reaches the loading area the game is over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By putting down material on a conveyor belt for a lane worker to work on you impede its progress towards the loading area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/robo-loader/blob-intro.gif&quot; alt=&quot;blob intro&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed that there are 2 sets of numbers on the left. The big number, as I mentioned before, represents how many blobs of material you would place on the given conveyor belt if you were to press enter. The second smaller set of numbers is a counter that counts down till you can place the maximum amount of blobs again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;We are now approaching the center of what this game is really about...&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is really about managing diminishing returns! Something that has a diminishing return means I get a decreased effect from doing the same thing repeatedly. In order to keep the workers from getting to the left side of the screen I need to think about what lanes and color combinations are available to me at a given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance I might be out of yellow blobs on lane 1 but I have plenty red blobs left on that lane, and I might be out of red blobs on lane 2 but I have plenty of yellow blobs left on that lane. A few seconds later that situation may reverse and I have to keep track of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;One more thing:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each color can only exist once per &amp;quot;column&amp;quot;. This prevents me from just spamming colors across the lanes at all times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets say that all conveyor belts have 12 cells on which we can place blobs. If I put a Yellow blob on cell 1 of lane 2 that means that all other lanes&amp;#39;s cell 1 are cleared of yellow blobs. If I put a yellow blob on lane 1 and immediately afterwards put a yellow blob on lane 2 the yellow blob on lane 1 will disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;At a glance:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When taken together the game is about juggling different colors on different lanes in order to keep the workers from reaching the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/images/robo-loader/average-game.gif&quot; alt=&quot;average game&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Tweaking it:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to write this in such a way that changing certain aspects of the game would be easy. I did this by creating engines that would update and render the game  generically, regardless of their structure or settings. I then created a default settings file in &lt;code&gt;lib/game-settings/board-settings&lt;/code&gt; that contained everything about the game that could be changed. All of the properties for each of the games components were set by the contents of this file so that if I wanted to change something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amount of lanes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;amount of cells to a lane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how long before diminsing returns reset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how fast workers moved up the lane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how long it took for a worker to clear a single blob&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the rate at which workers speed up making the game gradually harder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could easily do so and see how it affected the way the game plays&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Lessons:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was surprisingly easy to balance, I did not see that coming! It took me 5 minutes
of fiddling with the numbers and I had a playable. The hard part was to
make a fun game, or at the very least a game where the player had to focus on the mechanics that I
wanted him or her to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the time it takes for diminishing returns to reset on a given color/lane is too low
its easy to spam buttons until you get something set down for a lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the workers proceed up the lanes too slow the player can plan too far ahead which
colors he or she might put down, too fast and theres no time to think about what diminishing returns are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it takes a worker too long to consume a single blob the fact that blobs diminish becomes less powerful since it only takes one blob to set a worker back alot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I plan to eventually implement is some degree of randomness that might occasionally clear an entire lane of blobs but leave the diminishing returns for that lane intact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it sounds like changing stuff in the game and seeing for yourself might interest you I suggest
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HoffsMH/robo-loader&quot;&gt;pulling it down&lt;/a&gt; and trying for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mhecker.com/blog/robo-loader/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mhecker.com/blog/robo-loader/</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>gaming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping a programming notebook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Up until relatively recently I had not been embracing the &amp;quot;programmers notebook&amp;quot;. But it has a hold on me now.
I plan to go over what changed and how I got into the note-taking groove.
I also plan to go into why, in my opinion, pen and paper actually trumps all the other tools and mediums for note taking, even when, and perhaps especially when
the subject is software design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So upon coming into Turing we were told that keeping a notebook was a good idea.
I had already kept a programming notebook on and off  before but I couldn&amp;#39;t force myself
to use it in a meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of it has to do with taking notes on things that have nothing to do with software development. So before we start I want to say that there are still a number of software tools that I type text into to organize some aspect of my life. So if something seems weird to you later on keep in mind that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;evernote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for grocery lists, errand lists, pickup laundry etc..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;plain text files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that I keep encrypted, thoughts about life when I just need to write about feelings or when i get excited, some of which may form the drafts of future blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;google calender:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not that often, but to keep track of imporant events  of course!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What changed..&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This didn&amp;#39;t happen all at once and it took more than a fair amount of effort to get some of these habits going.
So without and further ado here is my list of things that made the programmers note-book work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started taking it out every time I work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seriously, you might think that would be obvious to me but the common occurrence was:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think of something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;realize my notebook isn&amp;#39;t on the desk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;debate whether or not the thought is worth writing down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;forget what I was thinking about and go back to working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I allowed myself to make it private(informal)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was thinking of the notebook as something that I should be able to scan or take a picture of, without reviewing, and post online. The real downfall of this wasn&amp;#39;t that I was editing myself but that I had to take extra time and brain power to think about each and everything I wanted to write down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By allowing the notebook to be a little bit closer to my stream of consciousness, I found that I was willing to write in it much more often while working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The notebook is a resource thats primarily for me after all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I stopped trying to control it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;ve seen some of my friends note-books, and online I&amp;#39;ve seen  &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/sent-hil/3444793&quot;&gt;pristine structure and legends for notebooks&lt;/a&gt; from other developers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have that sort of attention span or discipline  and the decision fatigue about how to categorize what type of thought I was having was deterring me from writing stuff down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I made it not just about programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I suddenly remember something important outside of programming such as an errand, I write it down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows me to put the thought away instantly. Because I know that its written down I don&amp;#39;t have to worry if I instantly forget it again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a sense this exactly what the notebook is for. To let me program more productively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not just when I need to remember something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I have a spare moment or I&amp;#39;m feeling lost about the direction I&amp;#39;m going in with my daily schedule or project direction, I read it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More often than not I haven&amp;#39;t forgotten  anything but the act of reading it acts as a confidence builder moving forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This means I start reaping the benefits of not feeling like I have to remember every little thing all the time, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FKTxC9pl-WM&quot;&gt;its all one tank&lt;/a&gt; after all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Advantages of a Physical Notebook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;In a sense, a notebook is every note-taking piece of software rolled into one. Want to make a thought tree? visual mnemonic device? bullet points?
draw lines between connected thoughts in a paragraph? I think that the reason this flexibility is so suited to programming is that the abstractions we use to reason about programming are varied and specific to each of us. If I ask three different developers to come up with an analogy or explanation of how they understand linked lists, I would probably get 3 very different outcomes. One might think of Russian nesting dolls, another might think of a congo line. What are the chances that all three developers could clearly articulate those analogies or explanations using a single software tool?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;So far the neatest thing about a physical notebook is that its habit forming on its own. There are a lot of habits that are good for you in software development but are hard to keep going. Once I started writing in it more often, I found that I wanted to write in it more often. I Can&amp;#39;t work without now. It&amp;#39;s honestly one of the best habits I&amp;#39;ve formed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mhecker.com/blog/keeping-a-programming-notebook/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mhecker.com/blog/keeping-a-programming-notebook/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tool</category>
        
        <category>productivity</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pry neato&#39;s</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is an adaptation of a lightning talk I gave. Its basically just some of the tools
and tricks I&amp;#39;ve learned about while using pry and ruby. Hopefully I will come back to it later and make it more like a blog and less like a talk outline. But for now just posting this for some friends!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some accompanying demo code available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HoffsMH/pry-lightning-talk&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Basic neato&amp;#39;s&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some random things I&amp;#39;ve found useful that can be used with pry out of the box.
* &lt;code&gt;whereami&lt;/code&gt; to remember where you are in your code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; executes terminal commands

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.ls&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.clear&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.git diff&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;.git status&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and yes we can get crazy &lt;code&gt;.ruby &amp;lt;some-other-file&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and assuming your pry doesn&amp;#39;t completely crash when an exception occurs because you are using pry-rescue.
* &lt;code&gt;wtf&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wtf?&lt;/code&gt; to display stack traces for an exception&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cat -ex&lt;/code&gt; to bring you to the line in your code where the exception occurs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can edit a file while in pry then continue to run through it with &lt;code&gt;edit &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;but first we should probably set out editor with&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Pry.config.editor = &amp;#39;atom&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;vim&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;whathaveyou&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or just include that line in &lt;code&gt;.pryrc&lt;/code&gt; in our home directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Other Neato&amp;#39;s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool ways of using pry.
* &lt;code&gt;binding.pry&lt;/code&gt; is just ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we can put a condition on whether or not it runs for when we know when something is going wrong but don&amp;#39;t want to type exit 231 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;].&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;element&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;element&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;232&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;binding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;pry&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can also get pry to be the default debugger in rails by including &lt;code&gt;pry-rails&lt;/code&gt; instead of just &lt;code&gt;pry&lt;/code&gt; in your gemfile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#gemfile&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:test&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&#39;pry-rails&#39;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle&lt;/code&gt; then type &lt;code&gt;rails c&lt;/code&gt; and you&amp;#39;re in pry and not irb!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things to install and try&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ariabov/pry-toys&quot;&gt;Pry-toys&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For when you need to test something for yourself really quick. Really usefull for understanding enumerables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt; gem install pry-toys
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#### Try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Hash&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;toy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# creates a toy has&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;toy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# creates a toy array of Time objects&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deivid-rodriguez/pry-byebug&quot;&gt;Pry-byebug&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for stepping through code.
Serves as a fine comb to step through and understand code one line at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;was originally a fork of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nixme/pry-debugger&quot;&gt;pry-debugger&lt;/a&gt; which &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/24395453/gem-install-debugger-error&quot;&gt;doesn&amp;#39;t work past Ruby version 2.x&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;code&gt;bash
gem install pry-byebug
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#### Try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;step&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Moves through code line by line&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;continue&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# completes rest of code&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ConradIrwin/pry-rescue&quot;&gt;Pry-rescue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from the author of this gem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;start a pry session when something goes wrong&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is actually a two parter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;gem install pry-rescue
gem install pry-stack_explorer
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;both must be installed to work properly
* #### Try&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;rescue &amp;lt;problematic ruby file&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;and yes it can be used with rails&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;rescue rails s
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 17:56:45 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.mhecker.com/blog/pry-neatos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.mhecker.com/blog/pry-neatos/</guid>
        
        
        <category>tool</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
